Guide to the Simon Bauer papers,1932-2002.
Bauer, Simon papers, 1932-2002
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Simon Bauer papers, 1932-2002.
14-8-3451
Simon Bauer
9 cubic ft.
Publications, subject files
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes publications and subject files.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Emeritus professor in the Dept. of Chemistry, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes publications and subject files.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bauer, Simon; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.Dept. of Chemistry.
Subjects:
Chemistry--Study and teaching.; Chemists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
  - #1. The Function of sin x/x, S. H. Bauer, J. Opt. Soc. Am. 22, 537 (1932). (Box 1)
  - #2. The Orientation of Unsymmetrical Molecules at Interfaces, S. H. Bauer and A. Pollack, J. Chem. Phys. 3, 401 (1935). (Box 1)
  - #3. A Simple Mass Spectrometer, S. H. Bauer, J. Phys.Chem. 39, 959 (1935). (Box 1)
  - #4. Products and Processes of Ionization in Methyl Chlorides as Determined by a Mass Spectrometer, S. H. Bauer and T. R. Hogness, J. Chem. Phys. 3, 687 (1935). (Box 1)
  - #5. Inhomogeneous Fields for Mass Spectrography, S. H. Bauer, Phys. Rev. 48, 917 (1935). (Box 1)
  - #6. An Analytic Method of Interpretation of Electron Diffraction Photographs of Gases, S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 4, 406 (1936). (Box 1)
  - #7. Note on Dipole Moments of Molecules in Solutions, S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 4, 458 (1936). (Box 1)
  - #8. The Absorption Spectrum of Methyl Alcohol Vapor in the Photographic Infrared, R. M. Badger and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 4, 469 (1936). (Box 1)
  - #9. Absorption Spectra of the Vapors of Twelve Alcohols and of Nitric Acid in the Region of the 0-H Harmonic Band at 9500, R. M. Badger and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 4, 711 (1936). (Box 1)
  - #10. The Structure of the Pentaborane B5 H9, S. H. Bauer and Linus Pauling, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 58, 2403 (1936). (Box 1)
  - #11. On the Application of the Raman-Kirshman Theory to Dipole moment Measurements by the Dilute Solution Method, H. 0. Jenkins and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 58, 2435 (1936). (Box 1)
  - #12. Remarks on the Spectra of Methyl Cyanide and Methyl Isocyanide, R.M. Badger and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 59, 303 (1937). (Box 1)
  - #13. An Extension of the Analytic Method of Analysis of Electron Diffraction Photographs of Gases, S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 5, 368 (1937). (Box 1)
  - #14. The Spectrum Characteristic of Hydrogen Bonds, R. M. Badger and S.H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 5, 369 (1937). (Box 1)
  - #15. The Structure of Diborane, S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 59, 1096 (1937). (Box 1)
  - #16. The Infrared Spectrum and Internuclear Distances in Methyl Acetylene, R. M. Badger and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 5, 599 (1937). (Box 1)
  - #17. Spectroscopic Studies of the Hydrogen Bond. I. A Photometric Investigation of the Association Equilibrium in the Vapor of Acetic Acid, R. M. Badger and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 5, 605 (1937). (Box 1)
  - #18. The Structure of the Hydrides of Boron. III. Borine Carbonyl and Borine Trimethylamine, S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 59, 1804 (1937). (Box 1)
  - #19. Spectroscopic Studies of the Hydrogen Bond. II. The Shift of the O-H Vibrational Frequency in the Formation of the Hydrogen Bond, R. M. Badger and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 5, 839 (1937). (Box 1)
  - #20. The O-H Band in the Vapors of Some Organic Acids and of Tertiary Amyl Alcohol in the Region 9700, S. H. Bauer and R. M. Badger, J. Chem. Phys. 5, 852 (1937). (Box 1)
  - #21. The Structures of the Hydrides of Boron. IV. B2,NH7, and B3,N3,H6. The Structure of Dimethylamine, S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 60, 525 (1938). (Box 1)
  - #22. The Structure of the Hydrides of Boron. V. Tetraborane B4,H10, and the Pentaborane B5,H11. S. H. Bauer, Abstract of paper presented before AAAS at Indianapolis (1937), J. Chem. Phys. 6, 176 (1938); J. Am. Chem. Soc. 60, 805 (1938). (Box 1)
  - #23. The Density of Energy States in Solids, S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 6, 403 (1938). (Box 1)
  - #24. (a) On the Swelling of Coal: A General Review and Progress Report. (b) Theoretical Study of the Process of Swelling and the Plastic Properties of Coal. Distributed as a private publication of the School of M.I., Pennsylvania State College. (Box 1)
  - #25. The Molecular Structure of Hydrogen Fluoride, S. H. Bauer, J. Y. Beach and J. H. Simons, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 61, 19 (1939). (Box 1)
  - #26. Inversion of the Partition Function to Determine the Density of Energy States, S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 7, 1097 (1939). (Box 1)
  - #27. The Structure of the Hydrides of Boron. VI. AlB3H12. J. Y. Beach and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 62, 3440 (1940). (Box 1)
  - #28. The Structures of Methyl Borate and Trimethyl Triborine Trioxane, Interatomic Distances in Boron Compounds, S. H. Bauer and J. Y. Beach, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 63, 1394 (1941). (Box 1)
  - #29. The Structures of Methylenecyclobutane and Hexamethylethane, S. H. Bauer and J. Y. Beach, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 64, 1142 (1942). (Box 1)
  - #30. Structures and Physical Properties of the Hydrides of Boron and of their Derivatives, S. H. Bauer, Chem. Rev. 31, 43 (1942). (Box 1)
  - #31. The Structures of Dimethyl Boron Fluoride and Methyl Boron Difluoride, S. H. Bauer and J. M. Hastings, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 64, 2686 (1942). (Box 1)
  - #32. Voltage Stabilizer for Electron Diffraction Power Supply, S. H. Bauer, J. M. Hastings, and D. P. MacMillan, Rev. Sci. Instr. 14, 30 (1943). (Box 1)
  - #33. Donor-Acceptor Bonding. II. An Electron Diffraction Investigation of the Structure of Dimethyl Ether-Boron Trifluoride, S. H. Bauer, G. R. Finlay, and A. W. Laubengayer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 65, 889 (1943). (Box 1)
  - #34. An Evaluation of the Sector Technique as Applied to the Diffraction of Electrons by Gases, S. H. Bauer, Phys. Rev. 64, 316 (1943). (Box 1)
  - #35. On the Structure of Dimethyl Ether-Boron Trifluoride, S. H. Bauer, G. R. Finlay, and A. W. Laubengayer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 67, 339 (1945). (Box 1)
  - #36. Inversion of Low Angle Scattering Data for Particle Size Distribution, S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 13, 450 (1945). (Box 1)
  - #37. The Raman and Ultraviolet Absorption Spectra of the Dimethyl Ether-Boron Trifluoride Complex, F. V. Dunderman and S. H. Bauer, 50, 32 (1946). (Box 1)
  - #38. The Structure of the Hydrides of Boron. VII. Beryllium Borohydride BeB2H8. G. Silbiger and S. J. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 68, 312 (1946). (Box 1)
  - #39. Comments on Reported Interatomic Distances in Fluorinated Hydrocarbons, S. H. Bauer, published by the A.E.C. as Publication Number MDDC-1494 (1946). (Box 1)
  - #40. An Electron Diffraction Investigation of the Structure of Difluorodiazine, S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 69, 3104 (1947). (Box 1)
  - #41. The Structures of the Hydrides of Boron. VIII. Decaborane, G. Silbiger and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 70, 115 (1948). (Box 1)
  - #42. A Compact Multiple way Metal Stopcock, S. H. Bauer, Rev. Sci. Instr. 19, 52 (1948). (Box 1)
  - #43. Boron Hydrides, S. H. Bauer, Encyclopedia of Chemical Technology, 11, 593 (1948). (Box 1)
  - #44. An Evaluation of Quantitative Procedures for the Estimation of Intensities of Diffracted Electrons, Technical Report, Project NR052-040, Task Order I, Contract N6ori213, (Feb. 1, 1949), S. H. Bauer, F. A. Keidel and R. B. Harvey. (Box 1)
  - #45. An Electron Diffraction Investigation of the Structures of Neopentyl Chloride and Silico-Neopentyl Chloride. The Determination of Intensities through the Use of a Rotating Sector, J. M. Hastings and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys.X18,X13 (1950). (Box 1)
  - #46. The Structure of Uranium Hexafluoride as Determined by the Diffraction of Electrons on the Vapors, S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 18, 27 (1950). (Box 1)
  - #47. The Structure of Hexamethylcyclotrisiloxane as Determined by the Diffraction of Electrons on the Vapor, E. H. (Weller) Aggarwal and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 18, 42 (1950). (Box 1)
  - #48. Reanalysis of the Electron Diffraction Data on Be(BH42), and Al(BH43). S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 72, 622 (1950). (Box 1)
  - #49. To Investigate the Structure of Some Boranes and Related Compounds by Electron Diffraction and to Develop Quantitative Procedures for Estimating Electron Diffraction Intensities. Final Report, Project NR052-040, Task Order I, Contract N6ori-213 (March 1, 1950), S. H. Bauer, F. A. Keidel, R. B. Harvey, K. P. Coffin, and J. Bergman. (Box 1)
  - #50. Some Effects of Nozzle Design on the Diffraction of Electrons by Gases, R. B. Harvey, F. A. Keidel, and S. H. Bauer, J. Appl. Phys. 21, 860 (1950). (Box 1)
  - #51. Apparatus for Imposing and Measuring Rapid Pressure Changes in Gases, K. P. Coffin and S. H. Bauer, Rev. Sci. Instr. 23, 115 (1952). (Box 1)
  - #52. Remarks on the Structure of Volatile Fluorides, S. H. Bauer, J. Phys. Chem. 56, 343 (1952). (Box 1)
  - #53. A Hydrodynamic Method for the measurement of Rates of Very Fast Reactions, S. H. Bauer, L. Farkas Memorial Volume, Research Council of Israel, Special Publi. No. 1, Jerusalem, p. 95 (1952). (Box 1)
  - #54. Kinetics of Fast Reactions. Technical Report to the Office of Naval Research, Parts I and II, Project NR051-242, Contract N6nr-264(17) (February 1, 1953), S. H. Bauer and Assistants. (Box 1)
  - #55. Thermodynamic and Kinetic Constants for the Diborane-Borine Equilibrium, S. H. Bauer, Allen Shepp, and R. E. McCoy, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 75, 1004 (1953). (Box 1)
  - #56. Thermodynamic Functions for Surfaces of Crystals, S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 75, 1004 (1953). (Box 1)
  - #57. Remarks made at the Symposium on Kinetics of Fast Rections (September 1952), S. H. Bauer, J. Phys. Chem. 57, 390, 402, 424 (1953). (Box 1)
  - #58. Errata: A Hydrodynamic Method for the Measurement of Rates of Very Fast Reactions, S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 21, 956 (1953). (Box 1)
  - #59. An Electron Diffraction Study of DiSulfur Decafluoride, R. B. Harvey and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 75, 2840 (1953). (Box 1)
  - #60. Energy Exchange in Molecular Collisions, B. Widom and S. H. Bauer, Bull. Am. Phys. Soc. 28, No. 2, p.42 (W7) (1953); J. Chem. Phys. 21, 1670 (1953). (Box 1)
  - #61. On Rate of Approach to Equilibrium, S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 21, 1888 (1953). (Box 1)
  - #62. Experimental Molecular Structures, S. H. Bauer and Per Anderson, Ann. Rev. Phys. Chem. 4, 233 (1953). (Box 1)
  - #63. Computation on Entropy Increments in Gaseous Bimolecular Associations. I. Donor-Acceptor Reactions, Allen Shepp and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 76, 265 (1954). (Box 1)
  - #64. Computation of Entropy Increments in Gaseous Bimolecular Associations. II. The Dimerization of Carboxylic Acids, and the Addition of Fluorine to Halogen Fluorides, L. Slutsky and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 76, 270 (19S4). (Box 1)
  - #65. An Electron Diffraction Study of Disulfur Decafluorodioxide, R. B. Harvey and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 76, 859 (1954). (Box 1)
  - #66. Relaxation Techniques for Vast Reactions. A Study of the Dissociation of Nitrogen Dioxide, S. H. Bauer and M. R. Gustavson, Disc. Faraday Soc., No. 17, 69 (1954). (Box 1)
  - #67. The Structures of Phenylboron Dichloride, B-trichloroborazole, and N-trimethylborazole as Determined by Electron Diffraction, K. P. Coffin and S. H. Bauer, J. Phys. Chem. 59, 193 (1955). (Box 1)
  - #68. Electron Diffraction Determination of Lattice Parameters of Polycrystalline Specimens Giving Broad Diffraction Peaks. I. Discussion of Technique and Analysis of Errors, G. G. Libowitz and S. H. Bauer, J. Phys. Chem. 59, 209 (1955). (Box 1)
  - #69. Electron Diffraction Determination of Lattice Parameters of Polycrystalline Speciments Giving Broad Diffraction Peaks. II. A Study of Nickel Oxide, G. G. Libowitz and S. H. Bauer, J. Phys. Chem. 59, 214 (1955). (Box 1)
  - #70. An Electron Diffraction Study of Ketene Dimer, Methylketene Dimer, and Propiolactone, Judith Bregman and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 77, 1955 (1955). (Box 1)
  - #71. Kinetics of Fast Reactions. Second Technical Report to the office of Naval Research, Project NR051-242, Contract N6onr-264(17) (July 1955), S. H. Bauer and Assistants. (Box 1)
  - #72. Energetics of the Boranes. I. The Heat of Reaction of Diborane with the Methylamines, and of Tetramethyldiborane with Trimethylamine; The Dissociation Energy of Diborane, R. E. McCoy and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 78, 2061 (1956). (Box 1)
  - #73. Energetics of the Boranes. II. Kinetics Consequences of the Diborane-Borane Equilibrium. Comments on the Decomposition of OC:BH3. S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 78, 5775 (1956). (Box 1)
  - #74. Energetics of the Boranes. III. The Enthalpy and Heat Capacity of Trimethylamine-Trifluoroborane as Determined by the Drop Method, S. H. Bauer and R. E. McCoy, J. Phys. Chem. 60, 1529 (1956). (Box 1)
  - #75. The Structures of Toluene, Phenylsilane, and Diphenyldichlorosilane, F. A. Keidel and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 25, 1218 (1956). (Box 1)
  - #76. Collisional Energy Exchange in Gases. Use of the Spectrophone for Studying Relaxation Processes in Carbon Dioxide, M. E. Jacox and S. H. Bauer, J. Phys. Chem. 61, 833 (1957). (Box 1)
  - #77. on the measurement of Concentration Gradients in Thin Films, S. H. Bauer, J. Colloid Sci. 12, 460 (1957). (Box 1)
  - #78. Review of recent work on the hydrides of boron, "Boron Hydrides and Related Compounds", S. H. Bauer, First Supplementary volume, Encyclopedia of Chemical Technology, cf. No. 41, p. 103 (December, 1957). (Box 1)
  - #79. Energetics of the Boranes. V. Prediction of Heats of Formation. Interconversions of the Boranes, S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 80, 294 (1958). (Box 1)
  - #80. A Book Review: Structure Reports for 1940-41, S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 80, 506 (1958). (Box 1)
  - #81. The Diffraction of Electrons by Thin Films. Final Technical Report to the Office of Naval Research, Project NR356-296, Contract Nonr401(06), (Feb. 1, 1958), S. H. Bauer and Assistants. (Box 1)
  - #82. Length of the Liquid Range for a Pure Substance: A Molecular Interpretation, S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Ed. 35, 289 (1958). (Box 1)
  - #83. Kinetic Studies of Hydroxyl Radicals in Shock Waves. I. The Decomposition of Water Between 2400ºK and 3200ºK, S. H. Bauer, G. L. Schott, and R. E. Duff, J. Chem. Phys. 28, 1089 (1958). (Box 1)
  - #84. Entropies and Energies of Dimerization of Alkali Metal Halides, S. H. Bauer, R. M. Diner, and R. F. Porter, J. Chem. Phys. 29, 991 (1958). (Box 1)
  - #85. An Intense Schumann-Runge Source, F. Waelbroeck and S. H. Bauer, J. Opt. Soc. Am. 49, 102 (1959). (Box 1)
  - #86. The Infrared Spectrum of Gaseous Trimethylamine, S. H. Bauer and M. Blander, J. Mol. Spec. 3, 132 (1959). (Box 1)
  - #87. Triatomic Linear Molecules Containing Carbon and Oxygen, Sulfur, Selenium or Tellurium. III. Absolute Intensity of the 03, Band of CSe2, T. Wentink, Jr. and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 31, 834 (1959). (Box 1)
  - #88. Electron Diffraction Techniques for the Study of Amorphous Systems. National Research Council publication of conference on Noncrystalline Solids (Sept. 3-5, 1958), J. Wiley and Sons, p. 53 (1950). Discussions therein by S. H. Bauer. (Box 1)
  - #89. Dipole Moments and Optical Dispersion of Perchlorofluorobutanes, Butadienes, Butenes, and Propylenes, Emile Rutner and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 82, 298 (1960). (Box 1)
  - #90. Kinetics of Reactions in Shock Tubes (including the Kinetics and Production of C. During the Pyrolysis of Ethylene, The Equilibrium Composition of the C/H System at Elevated Temperatures2, A survey of the Methods for the Chemical Analysis of Transient Species with Microsecond Resolution, The rate of Dissociation of Cyanogen .... etc.). Final Technical Report, WADD TR60107, to the Air Force on Contract AF33(616)-3839, Project 7013, Task 70346 (CU 7185). S. H. Bauer and Assistants. (Box 1)
  - #91. The Molecular Structure of Iodine Heptafluoride, R. E. LaVilla and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 33, 182 (1960). (Box 1)
  - #92. Molecular Structure of Lithium Chloride Dimer. Thermodynamic Functions of Li2,X2, (X = Cl, Br, I), S. H. Bauer, Tadashi Ino, and R. F. Porter, J. Chem. Phys. 33, 685 (1960). (Box 1)
  - #93. A Survey of the Methods for the Chemical Analysis of Transient Species with Microsecond Resolution, S. H. Bauer, N. C. Rol, and J. H. Kiefer, AGOSRGE Symposium, Proceedings of the conference on "Physical Chemistry in Aerodynamics and Space Flight" (September 1-3, 1959), Pergamon Press, Oxford (1961), p. 118. (Box 1)
  - #94. Electron Diffraction Studies of Gaseous Polyatomic Molecules at High Temperatures. Final Technical Report to the office of Naval Research, Project NR357-393, Contract Nonr-401(29), S. H. Bauer, R. F. Porter, and Tadashi Ino (April 15, 1961). (Box 1)
  - #95. A Study of the Emission Intensities of Cr Lines from Shocked Gases Containing Cr(CO)6, S. H. Bauer, J. H. Kiefer, and B. E. Loader, Can. J. Chem. 39, 1113 (1961). (Box 1)
  - #96. (Energetics of the Boranes. IV.) Kinetics and mechanisms for Acid-Base Reactions Involving Boranes, S. H. Bauer, Adv. Chem. Series, 32, 88 (1961). (Box 1)
  - #97. Chemical Kinetics: A General Introduction, S. H. Bauer, Special publication of the International Hypersonics Conference by the American Rocket Society, AFOSR, at MIT (Aug. 1961). A Progress in Astronautics and Rocketry, 7, 143-180 (1962). (Box 1)
  - #98. Kinetics of Chemical Reactions in Gases at High Temperatures Utilizing Shock Tube Techniques. (Incorporate papers No. 95, 99, 100, 101, 102, 107, etc.). Final Technical Report to the Air Force, on Contract AF33(616)-6694, Task 70321 (CU7345), S. H. Bauer and Assistants, Aero. Res. Lab. Off. of Aerospace Research, USAF, AR-100, December (1961). (Box 1)
  - #99. The High Temperature Pyrolysis of Ethylene; Kinetics of C2 Formation, Wing Tsang, S. H. Bauer, and F. Waelbroeck, J. Phys. Chem. 66, 282 (1962). (Box 1)
  - #100. The Dissociation Energy and Rate of Decomposition of C2N2, M. Cowperthwaite, Wing Tsang, and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 36, 1768 (1962). (Box 1)
  - #101. The Estimation of Molecular Parameters of C/H Fragments, M. Cowperthwaite and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 36, 1743 (1962). (Box 1)
  - #102. The Equilibrium Composition of the C/H System at Elevated Tempertures, R. E. Duff and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 36, 1754 (1962). (Box 1)
  - #103. Two book reviews: The Proton in Chemistry by R. P. Bell, Cornell University Press, Ithaca, NY (1959); and Structure and Properties of Thin Films, edited by C. A. Neugebauer, J. B. Newkirk, and D. A. Vermilyea, John Wiley & Sons, Inc., New York, NY (1959), S. H. Bauer, J. Electrochem. Soc. 109, 97C, 117C (1962). (Box 1)
  - #104. Design and Characteristics of a Parallel Incidence Electron Diffraction Apparatus, S. H. Bauer and K. Kimura, J. Phys. Soc. Japan 17, 300305 (1962). (Box 1)
  - #105. Rate of Decomposition of Azomethane in a Shock Tube, George Chiltz, Carl F. Aten, Jr., and S. H. Bauer, J. Phys. Chem. 66, 1426 (1962). (Box 1)
  - #106. Investigation of Condensation Processes Behind Normal Shocks by optical Methods A feasibility Analysis. Preliminary Report to the Air Force under Contract AF 49(648)-716 (CU7356), S. H. Bauer and Y. Timnat, March, 1962. (Box 1)
  - #107. Book Review: Crystallometry, by Terpstra and Codd, Published in J. Am. Chem. Soc. 84, 391 (1962). (Box 1)
  - #108. Book Review: Shock Tubes, by J. K. Wright, Published in the American Scientist, p. 215A (June 1962). (Box 1)
  - #109. Two Book Reviews: Molecular Spectroscopy, by Gordon M. Barow, McGraw Hill, New York, xiii and 318 (1962); and Elementary Introduction to Molecular Spectra, by Børge Bak, Interscience (Wiley), New York, xi and 144 (1962), published in Science 138, 128 (1962). (Box 1)
  - #110. Mechanism for Vibrational Relaxation at High Temperatures, S. H. Bauer and S. C. Tsang, Physics of Fluids 6, 182 (1963). (Box 1)
  - #111. Absorption Spectra at High Temperatures. I. The Ultraviolet Spectra of Shock Heated Cis and Trans 1,2 Dichloroethylene, S. H. Bauer, Helen Kiefer, and N. C. Rol, appeared in the Proc. Ninth Int. Symp. Combustion, Academic Press, New York, 1963, p.81. (Box 1)
  - #112. Studies with a Single-Pulse Shock Tube. I. The Cis-Trans Isomerization of Butene2, A. Lifshitz, S. H. Bauer, and E. L. Resler, Jr., J. Chem. Phys. 38, 2056 (1963). (Box 1)
  - #113. The Mass Spectra of Valence Tautomers, C. Lifshitz and S. H. Bauer, J. Phys. Chem. 67, 1629 (1963). (Box 1)
  - #114. Metal Halide Vapors: Structures and Thermochemistry, S. H. Bauer and R. F. Porter, in MOLTEN SALT CHEMISTRY, ed., M. Blander, Interscience Publ., New York (1964), p. 607. (Box 1)
  - #115. Absorption Spectra at High Temperatures. II. The Ultraviolet Spectra of C6H6 and C6 F6 Kinetics of the Pyrolysis of Benzene, S. H. Bauer and C. F. Aten, Jr., J. Chem. Phys. 39, 1253 (1963). (Box 1)
  - #116. Studies with a Single-Pulse Shock Tube. II. The Thermal Decomposition of Perfluorocyclobutane, A. Lifshitz, H. F. Carroll, and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 39, 1661 (1963). (Box 1)
  - #117. The Rates of Association of Lewis Acids and Bases in the Gas Phase, S. H. Bauer, J. V. Martinez, D. Price, W. J. Jones, and M. Blander, Adv. in Chem. Series (42), BORON-NITROGEN CHEMISTRY, Am. Chem. Soc., 1964, .35. (Box 1)
  - #118. Chemical Kinetics in Shock Tubes: A General Review, S. H. Bauer, Science 141, 867 (1963). (Box 1)
  - #119. The Structure of Gaseous Copper Nitrate as Determined by Electron Diffraction, R. E. La Villa and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 85, 3597 (1963). (Box 1)
  - #120. On the Density-Intensity Calibration in Electron Diffraction Studies, K. Kimura and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 39, 3171 (1963). (Box 1)
  - #121. The Structure of SF4 and SOF4 as Determined by Electron Diffraction, K. Kimura and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 39, 3172 (1963). (Box 2)
  - #122. An Electron Diffraction Study of XeF4, R. K. Bohn, K. Katada, J. V. Martinez, and S. H. Bauer, NOBLE GAS COMPOUNDS, Ed., H. H. Hyman, Chicago University Press (1963), p.238. (Box 2)
  - #123. Studies with a Single-Pulse Shock Tube. III. The Thermal Isomerization of CH3NC, A. Lifshitz, H. Carroll and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 86, 1488 (1964). (Box 2)
  - #124. The Absorption Spectrum of BH and BD in the vacuum Ultraviolet, S. H. Bauer, G. Herzberg, and J. W. C. Johns, J. Mol. Spectrosc. 13, 256 (1964). (Box 2)
  - #125. Collision Broadening of OH Emission Lines, Measured in the Infrared, S. H. Bauer and J. H. Jaffee, Xth Symp. (International) on Combustion, Mono of Maryland, 1965, p.499. (Box 2)
  - #126. The Ultraviolet Absorption Spectra of Perhalogenated Butadienes (1,3). A Free Electron Study, Emile Rutner and S. H. Bauer, J. Phys. Chem. 68, 1768 (1964). (Box 2)
  - #127. Vibrational Excitation in Some Four-Center Transition States, S. H. Bauer and E. L. Resler, Jr., Science 146, 1045 (1964). (Box 2)
  - #128. Isotope Exchange Rates. I. The Homogeneous Reaction Between NH3 and D2, A. Lifshiftz, C. Lifshitz, and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 87, 143 (1965). (Box 2)
  - #129. Isotope Exchange Rates. II. The Homogeneous Reaction Between C,H, and D., K. Kuratani and S. H. Bauer, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 87, 150 (1965). (Box 2)
  - #130. Thermal Decomposition of ClCN, D. Schofield, W. Tsang, and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Phys. 42, 2132 (1965). (Box 2)
  - #131. Physical Chemistry in the Engineering Curriculum, M. A. Paul and S. H. Bauer, J. Chem. Ed. 42, 196 (1965). (Box 2)
  - #132. Shock Waves A Review, S. H. Bauer, Ann. Rev. Phys. Chem. 16, 245 (1965). (Box 2)
  - #133. The Dynamics of Cryosorption Pumping, S. H. Bauer, P. Jeffers, J. Phys. Chem. 69, 3318 (1965). (Box 2)
  - #134. The Condensation of CN in an Expansion Wave, W. S. Watt and S. H. Bauer, 5th Shock Tube Symp.; Bull. Am. Phys. Soc. 10, 1151 (1965), Abs. SP10; J. Chem. Phys. 44, 1387 (1966). (Box 2)